KAT GOMOZOVA

Greater Seattle Area

Email: <u>kathy.gomozova@gmail.com</u> | Phone: 425-628-3959 | GitHub: <u>http://www.github.com/kgo87</u> LinkedIn: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/kgomozova</u> | Portfolio: <u>http://www.katgomozova.com</u>

SUMMARY

Passionate problem solver, software engineer and data scientist. 9+ years of diverse engineering experience, including civil engineering, data science, and software development. Coding skills include all areas of full stack web development, test-driven application development, data science, and Machine Learning. Strong communicator with skills in understanding requirements and solving ambiguous problems. Experienced leader in technical and functional roles.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, JavaScript (Node.js, jQuery, React), HTML/CSS

Tools and Frameworks: Azure ML, VisualStudio, Git, Cloud Computing, Colab/Jupyter notebooks

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Machine Learning Libraries: TensorFlow, Keras, ScikitLearn
Projects

Dance Class App | https://github.com/kgo87/DanceTeacher_db | https://dance-class-search.herokuapp.com/index Full-stack dance learning management system where users can search for dance classes, add, update and view information about dance classes and instructors. Technologies and frameworks used: MySQL, Express, Sequelize, JavaScript, Handlebars, Passport.

Restaurant App | https://node-handlebars-heroku-kat.herokuapp.com/https://node-handlebars-heroku-kat.herokuapp.com/https://node-handlebars-heroku-kat.herokuapp.com/full-stack application that allows users to save, update status and display the burger information stored in the database. Technologies and frameworks used: MySQL, express, JavaScript, Handlebars.

Weather Dashboard | https://github.com/kgo87/weather_dashboard | https://kgo87.github.io/weather_dashboard/
The application allows the user view current weather and 5-day forecast for the selected city. The project included front-end development, local storage and requests to third-party APIs.

WiDS 2020 Datathon Kaggle Competition | https://www.kaggle.com/c/widsdatathon2020/submissions
As a team of 4, developed a CatBoost classifier to predict patient survival using 100's of features from the first 24 hours of intensive care. The submission scored in the top 20%.

EXPERIENCE

ENGINEER | JACOBS ENGINEERING | BELLEVUE, WA | JUNE 2018 - PRESENT

- Developed a Neural Net using TensorFlow and Python to optimize usage of chemicals at a water treatment facility to reduce the Client's chemical cost by 10%.
- Automated hydrologic calculations, using Python, and improved processing time by 6x.
- Hands-on work for clients to deep dive into their historical operation and performance big data using Python.
- Developed classification model using Python and TensorFlow to determine the material source of the water pollutant
- Built a Monte Carlo model using Python to evaluate 10K+ scenarios of partial and complete failure for Bellevue's water supply pipes in case of an earthquake.

RESEARCH ANALYST - UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON | SEATTLE, WA | JAN 2018 - JUNE 2019

- Using Python, developed a predictive model based on multiple terabytes of data, to predict water supply and demand in the Seattle area over the next 50 years.
- Using Pandas and NumPy libraries estimated the range of total snow loss volume in the next 50-70 years.

ECOPOLYMER GROUP CONSULTING ENGINEERS | KHARKIV, UKRAINE | NOV 2008 - MAR 2015

- Leveraged present net worth and life-cycle costs to complete economic analysis on equipment.
- Coordinated activities for design and construction teams.
- Ensured equipment suppliers submittals adhered to client specifications and listed equipment for customs.

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate Program: University of Washington, Seattle, WA, 2021

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering: University of Washington, Seattle, WA, 2019

Certificate in TensorFlow in Practice: Coursera Specialization, Seattle, 2019

Master of Science in Applied Economics: Karazin Kharkiv National University, Ukraine, 2013